machinemart.co.uk 2006-09-27

# Privacy Statement

**Privacy Statement**

This privacy statement applies to the website [www.machinemart.co.uk](http://www.machinemart.co.uk/), operated by

Machine Mart Ltd  
211 Lower Parliament Street   
Nottingham

Nottinghamshire 

NG1 1GN   

Tel:      0870 770 7800 

Email:  [sales@machinemart.co.uk](mailto:sales@machinemart.co.uk)

**Your data is safe with us.   Unlike most companies we _DO NOT_ share your information with other companies for their commercial use. **

Machine Mart respects your privacy, and this is why we have taken the time to disclose our information collection practices and our privacy policy. 

**_Information we collect, and how it is used_**

Machine Mart collect data in order to help provide site users and customers with the best possible service. We do this in several ways. 

**Personal Information:**

Whenever you place an order we collect your name, postal address, email address and telephone number. 

We use this information to process your order, and communicate with you in respect of your order where necessary.  We collect credit or debit card information including the card type, card number, start date and expiry date in order to process your order. 

We also collect information when you request a catalogue, enter a competition or register for email updates. 

We may use the information collected to notify you about new products, money saving offers, news and changes to our website and web service. At each point where you are asked to provide us with personal information you will be given the opportunity to tell us that you do not want your personal information to be used in this way. If you later decide that you no-longer wish to receive such information from Machine Mart, you can "Unsubscribe" from our updates at any time (see "Unsubscribing").

We may also store and use information for the purposes of website and system administration, and fulfilment of customer service.  For example, we keep details of your purchase in order to maintain records relating to product warranties etc. 

We may analyse information collected for research, and for the development of our website and our services to benefit our website visitors and customers.  This may include building records of individual visitors, which are combined together for analysis of trends and patterns in the usage of our website. 

**Unsubscribing:**

If you later decide that you do not wish to receive such information from Machine Mart, you can "Unsubscribe" from our updates at any time.  Each e-mail you receive will contain details of how to unsubscribe. 

You must tell us the email address that you would like to unsubscribe.  If your email is redirected from one email address to another, you should tell us the address to which we send our email updates.  You can e-mail us at [unsubscribe@machinemart.co.uk](mailto:unsubscribe@machinemart.co.uk), or alternatively you can write to us at: 

E-mail updates - Unsubscribe

Marketing Department

Machine Mart Ltd

211 Lower Parliament St

Nottingham

NG1 1GN

**Sharing information:**

Machine Mart employs other companies to perform specific functions on our behalf.  Examples include the preparation and transmission of email updates, the delivery of packages, secure processing of payments etc.  These companies have access to information in order to perform their functions for Machine Mart, but may not use the information for any other purpose. 

Your information is safe with us.  _Machine Mart does not disclose information to other companies for their commercial use_. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are small programs that our website sends to your browser software, which may then be stored on your computer. 

Cookies are used to help our website recognize your browser, and provide a better website service to you.  For example, if you have visited our website and registered for our latest competition, a cookie will ensure that you do not see our advert for the competition on your subsequent visits to our site.  These cookies do not use personally identifiable information. 

Cookies are used to enable you to place an order on our website.  It is not possible to place an order on [www.machinemart.co.uk](http://www.machinemart.co.uk/) unless your browser software is set to accept cookies.  You can change your browser settings to accept or decline cookies.  See the section on _[cookies](http://www.machinemart.co.uk/faq.asp#004_whatarecookies)_ on our FAQ's page for details, or use the help button on your browser toolbar. 

We recommend that you adjust your browser settings to accept cookies, and leave them switched "on". 

**Information queries**

We collect, store and process information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

If you have any queries with regards to personal information collected by Machine Mart Ltd, please contact us at **[webprivacy@machinemart.co.uk](mailto:webprivacy@machinemart.co.uk)**

Or write to: 

**Website Privacy**

**Machine Mart Ltd**

**211 Lower Parliament Street** ****

**Nottingham** ****

**NG1 1GN**

**United Kingdom** ****
